Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 5929 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials
1955-1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees (NUHHCE)
Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union
5929 AV
13 cubic feet
12.5 linear ft.
Records (documents), audiovisual materials.
Primarily a video collection, this includes news footage, film of working conditions and strikes, documentary film about the Bread and Roses Cultural Project, film from several versions of the stage production "Take Care", healthcare crisis, AIDS, and May Day and Labor Day celebrations, among others.
6694318
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 12, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Scope and Contents
Primarily a video collection, this includes news footage, film of working conditions and strikes, documentary film about the Bread and Roses Cultural Project, film from several versions of the stage production "Take Care", healthcare crisis, AIDS, and May Day and Labor Day celebrations, among others.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records 5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 5929 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs
Labor unions -- Health facilities -- United States.; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees.; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees. Local 1199 Drug & Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.); Bread and Roses Cultural Project.
6694318
- Convention tape Nov '82 - Puerto Rican Hospital Workers, 1982; 1 (Box 2)
- Bread and Roses, 2 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Spanish version
- Unlabeled, 3 (Box 2)
- Bread and Roses / Produced by '1199', 4 (Box 2)
- Unlabeled, 5 (Box 2)
- The 1199 Story, 6 (Box 2)
- Edited Highlights of Bread and Roses: 6/25/1980, 7 (Box 2)
- Bread and Roses - 1199: Excerpts Edit, 8 (Box 2)
  MASTER
- Bread and Roses / Produced by '1199', 9 (Box 2)
- Year of the Child Spot / NBC/Channel 4 News - Friday, Feb. 2, 1979, 10 (Box 2)
- Working American Public Service Spot with Joan Mondale, 11 (Box 2)
  Dub
- Like a Beautiful Child: A Bread and Roses Video / Produced by Moe Foner, 12 (Box 2)
- Restoring Employees Rights is Good for America, 1993; 13 (Box 2)
- Bill Moyers' Journal, 14 (Box 2)
- 1199 Health Care Industry Class, 1 (Box 3)
  dub #1
- Patient Care - Edit #2 / District 1199, 2 (Box 3)
  dub
- Patient Care conference - Workshop II Ramon, 1979; 3 (Box 3)
  dub of tape #5 -- Dec. 1, 1979
- 1199 Health Care Industry Class, 4 (Box 3)
  dub #2
- Take Care, Take Care / performance at Long Island Jewish Medical Center during strike, 5 (Box 3)
- NC4SEGS - Hospital Show: 3/6/1979, 6 (Box 3)
- Patient Care Edit / Tom Clancy at 12/1/1979 Conference / Bread and Roses District 1199, 7 (Box 3)
- Apple Polishers - Channel 9: Take Care, Take Care -- April 1982, 8 (Box 3)
- Now it's my time / Union 1199 Retirement Program, 9 (Box 3)
- Patient Care Conference, 10 (Box 3)
  Final Cut -- dub #1
- City Edition: Ossie Davis, 11 (Box 3)
- Allentuck/Rosenblum Productions: Their Life's Sweat -- 10/20/1979, 12 (Box 3)
- Allentuck/Rosenblum Productions: Their Life's Sweat -- 10/30/1979, 13 (Box 3)
- LIJ Bread and Roses, 1982; 1 (Box 4)
  tape 2 -- 3/23/1982
- LIJ Bread and Roses, 1982; 2 (Box 4)
  tape 4 -- 3/23/1982
- LIJ Bread and Roses, 1982; 3 (Box 4)
  tape 1 -- 3/23/1982
- LIJ - Bread and Roses, 1982; 4 (Box 4)
  tape 5 - 3/23/1982
- LIJ - Bread and Roses, 1982; 5 (Box 4)
  tape 3 -- 3/23/1982
- Big Apple Minute - Images of Labor, 6 (Box 4)
- League Contract - 7/1982, 7 (Box 4)
- Capitol Protest: 2/8/1983, 8 (Box 4)
- Bless This House & Mimi Smith, 9 (Box 4)
- From Straight Talk, 10 (Box 4)
- 1199 Celebrates Labor Day: 9/3/1979, 11 (Box 4)
- Apple Polishers - Channel 9: Take Care, Take Care, April 1982, 12 (Box 4)
- Images of Labor - August 26, 1981 for Bruce Allen, 13 (Box 4)
  Channel 13
- Woman to Woman / Bread and Roses, 14 (Box 4)
- Disarming Art the contemporary Art Center: Sept. 1984, 15 (Box 4)
- Sonia Friedman Show - Jan. 1990, 1 (Box 5)
- Home care: a costly bargain, 2 (Box 5)
- St. Barnabas Strike: Sept. 1982, 3 (Box 5)
- Henry Nicholas Interview - Channel 7 Newsline: 11/7/1984, 4 (Box 5)
- 1199 News Excerpts for Moe Foner, 1984; 5 (Box 5)
- Ruby and Ossie Davis - Crazy Hattie Enters the Ice Age, 6 (Box 5)
- H83 - United Prof, Madison, Wi, 7 (Box 5)
- Dept. of Labor orders new election for 1199 Officers: 7/30/1985, 8 (Box 5)
- Phil Donahue Show: 1/21/1983, 9 (Box 5)
- Sunday, January 13, 1985, Channel 7 News; Sunday, January 13, 1985, Channel 5 News, 10 (Box 5)
- Brookdale RN Work stoppage 3/16/1987, 11 (Box 5)
  ch.4, ch.7, Ch. 11
- District 99C: 3/3/1983, 12 (Box 5)
- Press Conference, 1 (Box 6)
- Health Care for all New York, 2 (Box 6)
- 1199 - the history of a fighting union, 3 (Box 6)
- Labor Day Parade-Local 1199: Channel 2 News / WCBS-TV/New York, September 3, 1990, 4 (Box 6)
- Documentary on Local 1199, Channel 2: the People - 12/21/1989, 5 (Box 6)
- Take Care 3; Today / NBC-TV/Network, May 30, 1989, 6 (Box 6)
- Dennis Rivera-1199 / Face to Face with John Cardinal O'Connor // WCBS-TV/New York, October 1, 1989, 7 (Box 6)
- Health Care Crisis: We're Fighting - April 11, 1989, 8 (Box 6)
- Women of Hope: Latinas Abriendo Camino, 1996; 9 (Box 6)
- Dennis Rivera-President: News 4, New York / WNBC-TV/New York, October 4, 1989, 10 (Box 6)
- On the Move: Victory for Local 1199: May 1990, 11 (Box 6)
- May Day, 5/4/1990, 12 (Box 6)
- Local 1199 Hospital Workers, Visiones / WNBC-TV/New York: January 28, 1990, 13 (Box 6)
- Local 1199 and Hospital Negotiation: News 4 New York // WNBC-TV/New York -- October 4, 1989, 14 (Box 6)
- Hilton/Sucherman: Face to Face with Cardinal John O'Connor -- 9/21/1989, 15 (Box 6)
  Show #29
- Hospital Revue: Pt. I / Interviews with workers closeups, 1 (Box 7)
- Hospital Revue: Pt. II / Workshop interviews, 2 (Box 7)
- 1199 Albany Demonstration, 3 (Box 7)
- Take Care III / NBC-TV "Today Show" - 5/30/1989, 4 (Box 7)
  tape 1 of 2
- Take Care III / NBC-TV "Today" Show - 5/30/1989, 5 (Box 7)
  tape 2 of 2
- Local 1199 Election - News Four New York / WNBC-TV/NY: November 15, 1987, 6 (Box 7)
- Take Care, 7 (Box 7)
  dub/rough cut
- Hospital Workers: 8/28/1984, 8 (Box 7)
- Eyewitness News - 1/9/1985, 9 (Box 7)
  dub of Local 1199
- Take Care - 6/25/1989, 10 (Box 7)
- Home Care Workers / News 4 New York / WNBC-TV/New York: March 10, 1988, 11 (Box 7)
- Dennis Rivera "Visiones" / Host: Rafael PiRoman, 1 (Box 8)
- Women of Hope: Latinas Abriendo Camino, 1996; 2 (Box 8)
- Bread and Roses - Invisible no more: 6/23/1992, 3 (Box 8)
  English Only
- 1199 RNs on the Front Line, 4 (Box 8)
- Dennis Rivera footage from Profiles: Two Latin Activists, 5 (Box 8)
- On the Move Victory for Local 1199: May 1990, 6 (Box 8)
- Bread and Roses, 7 (Box 8)
  sound only [ Odetta Roberts found in a gallery]
- 1199 RNs on the Front Line, 8 (Box 8)
- 1199 RNs on the Front Line, 9 (Box 8)
- Best Talk - Dennis Rivera: 3/19/1992, 10 (Box 8)
- Dennis Rivera Visiones: 1990 / Two Latin Activists, 11 (Box 8)
- Tiempo - 3/13/1992, 12 (Box 8)
- Image of Labor, 13 (Box 8)
- Working Edit - 1199 Strike at L.I.J. Hospitals - 3/1982, 14 (Box 8)
  produced for On Line
- Labor News - Labor Day Street Fair: 9/1/1980, 15 (Box 8)
- Old Drug Div., 1 (Box 9)
- Count Down to a Contract: League Film 1976 Strike, 2 (Box 9)
- 1199 Delegate Assembly: tape 4 -- 8/26/1986, 3 (Box 9)
- 1199 Delegate Assembly: tape 6 -- 8/26/1986, 4 (Box 9)
- 1199 Delegate Assembly: tape 1 -- 8/26/1986, 5 (Box 9)
- 1199 Delegate Assembly: tape 2 -- 8/26/1986, 6 (Box 9)
- 1199 Delegate Assembly: tape 5 -- 8/26/1986, 7 (Box 9)
- 1199 Delegate Assembly: tape 3 -- 8/26/1986, 8 (Box 9)
- Helping To Care (Box 10)
  - Helping to Care, 1 (Box 10)
  - Bread and Roses: #4, 2 (Box 10)
    3" Film
  - League / CBS: 1976 -- #1, 3 (Box 10)
  - I Am Somebody / Bread and Roses, 4 (Box 10)
  - Hospital Strike / Bread and Roses, 5 (Box 10)
  - I Am Somebody / Bread and Roses, 6 (Box 10)
    property of District 1199
  - Testimony: Justice vs. J.P. Stevens, 7 (Box 10)
    Harold Mayer Productions
  - Like a Beautiful Child, 8 (Box 10)
  - Beautiful Child, 9 (Box 10)
- Bread and Roses #4 (Box 10)
- League / CBS 1976 (Box 10)
- I Am Somebody (Box 10)
- Hospital Strike (Box 10)
- I Am Somebody (Box 10)
- Testimony: Justice vs. J.P. Stevens (Box 10)
- Like a Beautiful Child (Box 10)
- Beautiful Child (Box 10)
- Unlabeled, 1 (Box 11)
  not in box at this time
- M.L. King / 1199, 2 (Box 11)
- District 1199, Hospital Workers Union: 7/16/1981, 3 (Box 11)
- District 1199, National Hospital Union: 6/4/1976, 4 (Box 11)
- District 1199 and Martin Luther King, 5 (Box 11)
- Coretta Key: 1970, 6 (Box 11)
- District 1199, National Hospital Union: 6/29/1976, 7 (Box 11)
- District 1199, National Hospital Union: 6/16/1976, 8 (Box 11)
- Commercial on John Vandercook CIO radio program. July 28, 1955 / Local 1199 Teen Time Program, 9 (Box 11)
- WABC - Jan. 17, 1955, Broadcast re. Rivera, 10 (Box 11)
- Local 1199 - Dr. King Spot, 11 (Box 11)
- Martin Luther King, 12 (Box 11)
- Elliot Godoff Reading: Tape #3, 13 (Box 11)
- Rubossie, 14 (Box 11)
- Rubossie / Bread and Roses, 15 (Box 11)
- Martin Dubin, 16 (Box 11)
- Leon Davis to Hospital Workers 1959 or 1962, 17 (Box 11)
- Leon Davis: #1 - July 22nd Meeting (1959?), 18 (Box 11)
- The Insurgents: Open Program, 19 (Box 11)
- Labor Day Interview Alma JohnLabor Day 1957, 20 (Box 11)
- Elliot Godoff Reading - Tape #1, 21 (Box 11)
- M.L. King at Hunter, 22 (Box 11)
- Godoff Memorial: Reel 2, 23 (Box 11)
- Leon Davis to Drugstore Members, 24 (Box 11)
- Homemakers Club: 4/10/1955, 25 (Box 11)
- You Have to Pay: A documentary about the Beth-El Hospital Worker's Strike, 26 (Box 11)
- Godoff Memorial: Headed and Tail, 27 (Box 11)
- Elliot Godoff Reading: tape #2, 28 (Box 11)
- Godoff Memorial: Reel 2, 29 (Box 11)
- Detroit Model, BMJ, Ford Assembly Plant, 1 (Box 12)
- Bread and Roses / Sam Levison: tape 1, 2 (Box 12)
- Bread and Roses / Leon Davis: tape #4 Interview at home, 3 (Box 12)
- Detroit Model - BMJ, Ford Assemble Plant, 4 (Box 12)
- Detroit Model, BMJ, Richard at home, 5 (Box 12)
- Bread and Roses / Sam Levinson - L.I.J. - tape 1, 6 (Box 12)
- Bread and Roses / Stanley Levison, 7 (Box 12)
- Detroit Model, BMJ, Ford Assembly, 8 (Box 12)
- Bread and Roses / Leon Davis Interview at home: tape 1, 9 (Box 12)
- Take Care - 2, 10 (Box 12)
- Take Care: 1, 11 (Box 12)
- Mrs. Coretta Scott King: March 9, 1965, 12 (Box 12)
- I Am Somebody, 13 (Box 12)
- Take Care: 3, 14 (Box 12)
- District 1199 / Bread and Roses Too: 5/23/1980, 15 (Box 12)
- Salute to Freedom: March 9, 1969, 16 (Box 12)
- Mrs. Coretta Scott King: March 9, 1969, 17 (Box 12)
- Mrs. Coretta Scott King: 3/9/1969, 18 (Box 12)
- Local 1199, 19 (Box 12)
  Spanish and English spots
- District 1199, Hospital Workers Union: 7/6/1981, 20 (Box 12)
- M.L. King, 21 (Box 12)
- District 1199 and Martin Luter King, 22 (Box 12)
  for Tuomey Hospital and St. Rafael's Hospital
- Unlabeled, 23 (Box 12)
- Unlabeled, 24 (Box 12)
- Unlabeled, 25 (Box 12)
- Irwin Corey at the 5 Spot, 26 (Box 12)
- Like It Is / Sunday, January 13, 1985, 1 (Box 13)
- Hospital Union Election: WNBC-TV, News, January 13, Sunday, 2 (Box 13)
- Violence at Local 1199, 3 (Box 13)
- Bread and Roses / Leon Davis in Office: tape 1, 4 (Box 13)
- Bread and Roses / Leon Davis: tape 4, 5 (Box 13)
- Bread and Roses / Sam Levinson: tape 3, 6 (Box 13)
- Bread + Roses Sam Levinson LIJM Tape #2, 7 (Box 13)
  #93
- Bread + Roses - S. Levinson at W.P., L.I.J.H. Tape #5, 8 (Box 13)
  #17
- Bread + Roses S. Levinson Tape #3, 9 (Box 13)
  #15
- Bread + Roses - S. Levinson Memorial Tape #5, 10 (Box 13)
- Bread + Roses S. Levinson Memorial Tape#2, 11 (Box 13)
- Bread + Roses S. Levinson Memorial Tape #1, 12 (Box 13)
  #139
- Oral History Workshop June 23, 1 (Box 14)
- Labor Day Street Fair Tape #2, 2 (Box 14)
- Bread + Roses S. Levinson Memorial Tape #3, 3 (Box 14)
  #141
- Bread + Roses -S. Levinson Tape #4, 4 (Box 14)
  #21
- Bread + Roses S. Levinson at LIJH Tape #4, 5 (Box 14)
  #16